<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.github.prepushchecker</id>
    <name>Pre-Push Compilation Checker</name>
    <version>1.8.2</version>
    <vendor email="aswin2kumarforme@gmail.com" url="https://github.com/eziocode/IntelliJ-Plugins">eziocode</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Blocks git pushes when your code has compilation errors — before they reach the remote.</p>

        <h3>How it works</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>IDE Push Guard:</b> Hooks into the IntelliJ Git Push dialog via the
                <code>prePushHandler</code> extension point. Checks whether the IDE already knows
                about problems in the pushed files, then compiles the affected modules and their dependents.
                A full project build is used only when build files or file deletions are involved.</li>
            <li><b>Strict A/B preflight:</b> When enabled, the plugin escalates only risky pushes
                to exact pushed-snapshot validation, so local-only dependent changes cannot silently
                hide a compile failure in the pushed commits. A symbolic check (<code>git diff HEAD</code>
                of unpushed local files vs. HEAD content of pushed files) catches A/B mismatches in
                milliseconds without invoking a build.</li>
            <li><b>Auto-retry on success / choice dialog on failure:</b> When the background pre-push
                check passes, the plugin runs <code>git push</code> automatically per repository root.
                When errors are found, a modal dialog offers Reset Commit / Push Anyway / Leave Commit
                / Cancel.</li>
            <li><b>Terminal Push Guard:</b> On project open, the plugin installs a managed
                <code>pre-push</code> Git hook that reuses the running IDE compiler when available,
                then falls back to a fast Gradle or Maven compile before allowing any push from a
                terminal or external git client. The fallback path stashes the working tree first
                so the build sees only HEAD content and A/B mismatches still surface.</li>
        </ul>

        <p><b>Important:</b> The plugin is a local preflight. Required Merge Request CI with
        branch protection should remain the authoritative gate before changes reach main/master.</p>

        <h3>Features</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Smart compile scope — changed modules plus dependent modules by default, project-level when necessary</li>
            <li>Debounced warmup compiles — keeps the IDE compiler cache hot for near-instant pushes</li>
            <li>IDE problem check — skips compilation if IntelliJ already reports errors</li>
            <li>Navigable error dialog — double-click any error to jump to the source file</li>
            <li>Refresh action — re-run the check from the block dialog without cancelling the push</li>
            <li>Compilation Checker tool window — side panel showing errors with file navigation</li>
            <li>Gradle (wrapper or system) and Maven (wrapper or system) support</li>
            <li>Optional stash fallback for strict A/B validation when detached worktrees are unavailable</li>
            <li>Respects <code>PRE_PUSH_CHECKER_COMMAND</code> env variable for custom check commands</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>AI Commit Message Generator <em>(new in 1.8.0)</em></h3>
        <p>Generate a commit message from your staged diff with one click — from the Git Commit dialog
        toolbar or the Compilation Checker tool window. The button greys out automatically when there
        are no changes.</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>9 providers:</b> JetBrains AI, OpenAI, Anthropic, Gemini, Ollama, Codex (ChatGPT account),
                GitHub Copilot, Claude CLI, llm CLI</li>
            <li><b>Codex (ChatGPT Account):</b> reads <code>~/.codex/auth.json</code> — sign in once
                with the Codex desktop app, no API key needed</li>
            <li><b>Custom rules:</b> Conventional Commits, max length, ticket prefix, language, scope, extra instructions</li>
            <li><b>Team rules file:</b> commit <code>.github/commit-instructions.md</code> to share
                prompt rules with your whole team</li>
            <li><b>API keys in PasswordSafe</b> — never written to plain XML state</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Requirements</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>IntelliJ IDEA 2023.3 or later</li>
            <li>Java 17+</li>
            <li>Java or Kotlin (JVM) project</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h3>1.8.1 — Stability &amp; API compatibility fixes</h3>

        <h4>Added</h4>
        <ul>
            <li><b>ChatGPT browser OAuth device sign-in.</b> The Codex settings card now has
                <em>Sign In</em>, <em>Sign Out</em>, and <em>Refresh</em> actions backed by a full
                OAuth 2.0 device-authorization flow. The browser opens for code approval, the
                plugin polls for the token in the background, and the result is stored in
                PasswordSafe.</li>
            <li><b>CLI auth status labels.</b> The settings cards for GitHub Copilot, llm CLI, and
                Claude CLI now show a live auth/availability status so you can confirm a provider
                is ready without leaving the IDE.</li>
        </ul>

        <h4>Fixed</h4>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Multi-repo diff collection:</b> AI commit prompts now gather diffs from all Git
                roots (staged → unstaged → HEAD), fixing blank messages in multi-root projects and
                mono-repos with sub-modules.</li>
            <li><b>EDT freeze on Codex auth refresh:</b> auth-file reads and status checks moved
                to a background thread; label updates on the EDT.</li>
            <li><b>Browse listener wiring</b> for the rules-file picker — path was not populated
                in some IDE versions.</li>
            <li><b>Commit control <code>ClassCastException</code></b> in the Git Commit dialog
                on recent platform builds.</li>
            <li><b>OAuth browser launch</b> now works on Linux and older macOS JDKs via
                <code>xdg-open</code> / <code>open</code> fallbacks.</li>
        </ul>

        <h4>Changed</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>Commit message injection uses the stable <code>CommitWorkflowUi</code> API.</li>
            <li>AI plugin detection uses <code>PluginManagerCore</code> class-loader check instead
                of the deprecated <code>isEnabled()</code>, eliminating false "not available"
                warnings on current IDE versions.</li>
            <li>OAuth token-refresh retry removed — stale token now fails fast and prompts
                re-authentication.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.8.0 — AI Commit Message Generator</h3>

        <h4>New feature: AI Commit Message Generator</h4>
        <p>Generates a ready-to-use git commit message from staged (or HEAD) diffs with one click.
        Accessible from the ⚡ button in the Compilation Checker tool window and from the Git Commit
        dialog toolbar (<em>same row as the Copilot button</em>). The button is greyed out
        automatically when there are no staged or local changes.</p>

        <h4>Nine AI providers</h4>
        <ul>
            <li><b>JetBrains AI</b> — uses the AI Assistant plugin when installed (optional soft dependency).</li>
            <li><b>OpenAI</b> — calls <code>gpt-4o</code> (or any configured model) via API key.</li>
            <li><b>Anthropic</b> — calls Claude 3.5 Sonnet via API key.</li>
            <li><b>Google Gemini</b> — calls Gemini 1.5 Flash via API key.</li>
            <li><b>Ollama</b> — local model at <code>localhost:11434</code>, no key needed.</li>
            <li><b>Codex (ChatGPT Account)</b> — reads <code>~/.codex/auth.json</code> written by
                the Codex desktop app. No API key required; sign in once with your ChatGPT account
                in the Codex app and the plugin uses that session automatically.</li>
            <li><b>GitHub Copilot</b> — calls the Copilot Chat API using <code>gh auth token</code>.
                Requires GitHub CLI and an active Copilot subscription.</li>
            <li><b>Claude CLI</b> — reads <code>ANTHROPIC_API_KEY</code> from your shell environment
                or PasswordSafe and calls the Anthropic API directly.</li>
            <li><b>llm CLI</b> — wraps Simon Willison's <code>llm</code> tool (60+ model providers
                via plugins). Install with <code>pip install llm</code>.</li>
        </ul>

        <h4>Custom commit message rules</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>Conventional Commits format (<code>feat:</code>, <code>fix:</code>, …)</li>
            <li>Max subject line length, prefix/ticket template, language/tone</li>
            <li>Auto-detect scope from changed file paths</li>
            <li>Free-form extra instructions appended to every prompt</li>
        </ul>

        <h4>Project-level rules file</h4>
        <p>Place <code>.github/commit-instructions.md</code> (or <code>COMMIT_RULES.md</code>) in
        the project root and commit it — the plugin appends it to the AI prompt automatically so
        the whole team shares the same conventions. The Settings page has a file browser with
        project-relative path storage and a live exists/missing status label.</p>

        <h4>Settings page</h4>
        <p>Settings → Tools → <em>Pre-Push Checker — AI Commit Message Generator</em>:
        per-provider auth, auto-detect buttons, Codex live sign-in status, Test Connection,
        model overrides, and all rule options. API keys stored in PasswordSafe.</p>

        <h4>Security fix</h4>
        <p>Shell injection guard reinstated in <code>CliPathResolver</code>: only bare executable
        names matching <code>[A-Za-z0-9._+-]+</code> are passed into <code>sh -c</code> scripts,
        blocking injection via user-controlled Settings values.</p>

        <h4>Bug fixes</h4>
        <ul>
            <li><b>CLI auto-detection:</b> sources shell rc files and probes Homebrew, npm-global,
                asdf, pip, Cargo — fixes "tool not found" when IntelliJ has a stripped GUI PATH.</li>
            <li><b>Codex infinite hang:</b> dropped the PTY subprocess approach; now calls OpenAI
                API directly using the ChatGPT OAuth token from <code>~/.codex/auth.json</code>.</li>
            <li><b><code>node: No such file or directory</code>:</b> shell-augmented PATH is now
                injected into all CLI subprocess environments.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.7.2</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Consistent <code>.kts</code> handling:</b> Kotlin script files are now
                recognized as compilable sources across both the in-IDE push handler and the
                external loopback server, matching the existing behaviour of the loopback
                server's file resolver. Build scripts such as <code>build.gradle.kts</code> and
                <code>settings.gradle.kts</code> remain classified as build files and continue
                to escalate to a project compile.</li>
            <li><b>Stricter loopback protocol:</b> the per-project pre-push server now requires
                an exact <code>CHECK</code> request instead of any line starting with
                <code>CHECK</code>, rejecting malformed or unexpected client traffic with a
                clear <code>ERR unknown-request</code> reply.</li>
            <li><b>No more leaked snapshot subprocesses on cancel:</b> when the user cancels a
                strict A/B snapshot validation mid-build (or any unexpected error occurs while
                waiting for git / Gradle / Maven), the spawned process is force-destroyed
                before the exception propagates, preventing background Gradle/Maven processes
                from outliving the cancelled check.</li>
            <li><b>Atomic port-file writes:</b> the loopback server's <code>server.port</code>
                file is now written via a temp file and atomic rename, so concurrent hook
                reads can never observe a zero-byte or partially-written port and silently
                fall back to the build-tool path.</li>
            <li><b>External hook log fingerprint cache no longer leaks across project
                open/close cycles:</b> the static dedup map (used to avoid re-parsing the same
                hook log on repeated VFS events) now drops its entry when the project is
                disposed.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.7.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Dedicated repair-hook icon:</b> the Compilation Checker tool window now uses a
                plugin-specific repair icon for the Recheck / Repair Git Hooks action instead of
                the generic refresh icon.</li>
            <li><b>Stale build-output retry:</b> if external Maven/Gradle fallback reports
                <code>bad class file</code> / <code>NoSuchFileException</code> errors from
                <code>target/classes</code>, <code>target/test-classes</code>, or
                <code>build/classes</code>, the hook refreshes generated class output and retries
                once before blocking so the cached log reflects the updated compile result.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.7.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Hook repair action:</b> the Compilation Checker tool window can repair and
                normalize managed Git hooks from the IDE, restoring missing or stale hook wiring
                without a manual reinstall.</li>
            <li><b>Improved <code>core.hooksPath</code> handling:</b> hook installation, repair,
                exclude cleanup, and current-state inspection now resolve custom hook directories
                and shared git directories more reliably, including canonical path comparisons for
                symlinked hook locations.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.6.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Clean-commit ledger:</b> a successful compile now records the verified HEAD SHA.
                After a rebase, merge, or pull that fast-forwards onto an already-verified upstream
                commit, the pre-push handler reuses the cached clean verdict instead of recompiling.
                Backed by a new <code>GitOperations</code> utility that inspects local git state
                (HEAD SHA, merge/rebase-in-progress, upstream tracking) without invoking external
                git for every check.</li>
            <li><b>Optional pre-compile rebase advisory:</b> when enabled
                (<code>prepushchecker.rebasePrecheck.enabled</code>, off by default), the plugin
                fetches each push root before scheduling the compile and prompts the user to
                rebase first if the remote is ahead. Ensures the build runs against the integrated
                tree so locally-clean-but-remotely-stale pushes do not surprise CI. Off by default
                because every push would otherwise pay a network round-trip.</li>
            <li><b>Repo-change-driven warmup compile:</b> branch switches, fetches, pulls, and
                rebases now trigger a debounced background project compile (30s cooldown absorbs
                bursts of state-change events from a single git operation). The compiler cache is
                hot for the integrated tree by the time the user pushes, turning most
                post-VCS-operation pushes into no-ops.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.5.3</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Generated getter/setter/builder false positives fixed:</b> when terminal,
                force-push, or GUI git client fallback compilation reports only generated-style
                <code>get*</code>, <code>set*</code>, <code>is*</code>, or <code>*Builder</code>
                missing-symbol errors, the hook now retries once with full compile scope before
                treating the output as a non-blocking generated-symbol false positive. This avoids
                the common &ldquo;first push fails, second push succeeds&rdquo; flow.</li>
            <li><b>Force Push retry fixed:</b> the plugin's force-push action now writes the
                one-shot bypass token before running <code>git push --force-with-lease</code>, so
                the retry is not blocked again by the managed pre-push hook.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.5.2</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>First-time warmup compile:</b> on the first project open after plugin install,
                a full background compile now runs automatically once indexing finishes. This primes
                the compiler cache so the first push from a terminal or GUI git client (Sublime Merge,
                SourceTree, GitHub Desktop) immediately reuses IntelliJ's incremental result instead
                of falling back to Maven/Gradle with a cold cache. Subsequent opens are unaffected.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.5.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>External push race fix (Sublime Merge / terminal):</b> the managed hook now
                waits longer for IntelliJ's local compiler socket before falling back to Maven/Gradle,
                preventing first-attempt false failures that succeeded on immediate retry.</li>
            <li><b>Generated-symbol fallback rescue:</b> when build-tool fallback reports
                getter/setter-style generated symbol errors (<code>get*</code>, <code>set*</code>,
                <code>is*</code>) and IntelliJ is running, the hook retries IntelliJ incremental
                compile once before aborting the push.</li>
            <li><b>Explicit fallback diagnostics:</b> hook logs now include the reason IntelliJ
                incremental compile was unavailable, so external push failures are easier to debug
                from <code>.idea/pre-push-checker/last-run.log</code>.</li>
            <li><b>Proactive uninstall cleanup:</b> the plugin now tracks managed repos and cleans
                their managed hook/cache/exclude artifacts during uninstall, including repos that are
                not currently open in the IDE.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.5.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Self-cleanup on uninstall:</b> when the plugin is uninstalled, a global marker
                (<code>~/.prepush-checker/installed</code>) is removed. Orphaned hooks in repos
                that were not open during uninstall now detect the missing marker on the next push
                and automatically remove themselves, the managed hook script, the cache directory,
                and the <code>.git/info/exclude</code> block. No manual cleanup needed.</li>
            <li><b>Push Anyway (IDE):</b> the compilation error dialog now includes a
                <em>Push Anyway</em> button in both the synchronous (cached errors, IDE problems)
                and background compilation paths. A one-shot bypass token is written so the git
                hook also allows the push through.</li>
            <li><b>Force Next Push (terminal / Sublime Merge / external clients):</b> a new toggle
                action in the Compilation Checker toolbar lets users skip the compilation check for
                the next push attempt. The bypass is single-use (consumed on the next push) and
                expires after 1 hour to prevent stale flags.</li>
            <li><b>Settings panel reorganized:</b> checkboxes are now grouped under a titled
                &ldquo;Settings&rdquo; border for a cleaner, more organized look.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.4.6</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>External hook now waits for a running IntelliJ before fallback:</b> when the
                first IDE socket probe fails, the managed pre-push hook now detects an active
                IntelliJ process and retries the IDE compile request for a short window before
                dropping to Gradle/Maven fallback. This reduces false fallback usage when the IDE
                is running in the background and the loopback service is still initializing.</li>
            <li><b>Fallback compile cache for unchanged HEAD:</b> when IntelliJ is unavailable and
                the hook uses build-tool fallback, successful results are now reused for identical
                HEAD + compile mode (main/test/all). Repeated pushes without new commits avoid
                redundant backend compiles while preserving existing failure behavior.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.4.5</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>External IntelliJ fast-path false positives fixed:</b> terminal,
                Sublime Merge, and other external git clients no longer block pushes from
                stale IntelliJ editor problem-cache entries. The loopback server now reuses
                only cached successful compile verdicts; cached failures are rechecked with
                <code>CompilerManager.make</code> before the hook reports an error. This
                prevents stale generated-symbol failures for Lombok-style getters, setters,
                and builders from persisting until the user manually runs the IntelliJ
                compilation check. If the external fast-path's scoped make still reports
                errors, it now retries once with the same project-scope make used by the
                tool-window compilation check before blocking the push.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.4.4</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Lombok ghost errors in the Maven fallback fixed:</b> when the IDE socket
                is unreachable and the hook (or the in-IDE strict snapshot guard) falls back
                to <code>mvn</code> / <code>./mvnw</code>, Maven's incremental compiler could
                re-compile a consumer against a stale <code>target/classes</code> copy of an
                <code>@Getter</code> / <code>@Setter</code> class — emitting false
                <code>cannot find symbol</code> errors (e.g. <code>setCloseIcon</code>,
                <code>setFromSheetView</code>, <code>isFromSheetView</code>) immediately
                after a merge that introduced new Lombok-generated members. Both Maven
                invocation sites now pass
                <code>-Dmaven.compiler.useIncrementalCompilation=false</code> so annotation
                processing always sees fresh sources. The IDE fast path
                (<code>PrePushLocalServer</code> &rarr; <code>CompilerManager.make</code>)
                was unaffected and is still used whenever IntelliJ is running.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.4.3</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>GUI git client PATH reconstruction:</b> the managed hook now sources the
                user's shell rc files (<code>.zshenv</code>, <code>.zprofile</code>,
                <code>.zshrc</code>, <code>.bash_profile</code>, <code>.bashrc</code>,
                <code>.profile</code>) and appends known install locations
                (<code>/opt/homebrew/bin</code>, SDKMAN, jenv, asdf,
                <code>$MAVEN_HOME/bin</code>, <code>$GRADLE_HOME/bin</code>) so that
                <code>mvn</code> and <code>gradle</code> resolve correctly when the hook is
                launched from Sublime Merge, SourceTree, GitHub Desktop, or any other GUI
                client that strips the user's interactive PATH. No effect on repos that ship
                a <code>./mvnw</code> or <code>./gradlew</code> wrapper.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.4.2</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>IntelliJ 2026.1 fix:</b> All four <code>projectActivity</code> entrypoints
                (managed pre-push hook installer, external hook log loader, local TCP server,
                warmup service) are now Kotlin <code>ProjectActivity</code> implementations
                that delegate to the existing Java logic. IntelliJ 2026.1 silently stopped
                invoking Java <code>ProjectActivity</code> implementations, which caused the
                local TCP server to never start — terminal / Sublime Merge / SourceTree pushes
                fell through to the raw Maven/Gradle fallback (and surfaced false "cannot find
                symbol" errors in projects whose Maven build relies on the IDE for Lombok-style
                annotation processing). After upgrading and restarting the IDE,
                <code>.idea/pre-push-checker/server.port</code> is written again and external
                pushes reuse IntelliJ's incremental compiler.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.4.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Marketplace compatibility cleanup:</b> removed deprecated
                <code>PerformInBackgroundOption</code> usage from background pre-push and
                auto-retry tasks while preserving always-background behavior. Plugin Verifier
                for IntelliJ IDEA 2026.1.1 now reports the plugin as compatible without
                deprecated API warnings.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.4.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Symbolic A/B detection:</b> the strict guard now scans <code>git diff HEAD</code>
                of unpushed local files for newly added method/class/field declarations and checks
                HEAD content of pushed files for word-boundary references. Catches the canonical A/B
                case (push references a symbol defined only in an unpushed local edit) instantly,
                without invoking a build.</li>
            <li><b>macOS path normalization:</b> snapshot output now strips both
                <code>/var/folders/...</code> and <code>/private/var/folders/...</code> forms so
                <code>filterSnapshotErrors</code> retains errors actually in pushed files.</li>
            <li><b>Auto-retry push on success:</b> when the background pre-push check passes, the
                plugin runs <code>git push</code> per repository root with non-interactive credentials
                (<code>GIT_TERMINAL_PROMPT=0</code>), <code>/dev/null</code> stdin, and a 120s timeout.
                Per-push elapsed-ms is logged to <code>idea.log</code>.</li>
            <li><b>Failure-choice dialog:</b> when errors are found, a modal dialog offers
                Reset Commit (soft-reset the pushed commits, keep changes), Push Anyway, Leave Commit,
                or Cancel.</li>
            <li><b>HEAD-snapshot stash in the external pre-push hook fallback:</b> when the IDE
                socket is unreachable, the hook stashes the working tree before running Gradle/Maven
                so the build sees only HEAD content; an <code>EXIT INT TERM HUP</code> trap guarantees
                stash pop on any interrupt. Closes the A/B coverage gap when the IDE is closed and
                pushes happen via terminal / Sublime Merge / GitHub Desktop.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.3.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Risk-scoped strict A/B dependency guard:</b> the side-panel toggle now escalates
                only when local source/build changes can plausibly mask pushed-snapshot failures.
                Risky pushes are validated against committed <code>HEAD</code> in a clean temporary
                worktree; an explicit advanced stash fallback is available when worktrees cannot be
                created.</li>
            <li><b>CI remains authoritative:</b> required Merge Request CI and branch protection are
                documented as the non-bypassable safety net before main/master accepts changes.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.3.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>External pushes reuse IntelliJ's incremental compiler:</b> terminal and GUI-client
                pushes now contact a local loopback server when the IDE is open, then fall back to
                Gradle or Maven if IntelliJ is unavailable.</li>
            <li><b>Zero-cost warmup path:</b> debounced background compiles after source saves keep
                compiler caches hot so most pre-push checks reuse a fresh verdict.</li>
            <li><b>Stronger dependency coverage:</b> targeted compile scopes now include dependent
                modules, catching caller-side breakage without forcing full project builds for
                ordinary source changes.</li>
            <li><b>Bounded error retention:</b> compiler errors and external hook log entries are
                compacted, deduplicated, and truncated where needed to keep memory usage predictable.</li>
            <li><b>Repository cleanliness:</b> plugin-owned hook/log/cache paths are excluded via
                repo-local <code>.git/info/exclude</code> and cleaned up when the plugin is disabled
                or uninstalled.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.2.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>External push guard (terminal, Sublime Merge, SourceTree, GitHub Desktop, etc.):</b>
                hook installation now resolves the real hooks directory via <code>git rev-parse --git-path hooks</code>,
                so it works in worktrees, submodules, and repos that set <code>core.hooksPath</code>.</li>
            <li><b>Stricter external check:</b> the hook now also compiles test sources
                (<code>classes testClasses</code> / <code>test-compile</code>) so test-only breakage is caught.</li>
            <li><b>Errors from external pushes surface inside IntelliJ:</b> the hook writes a log to
                <code>.idea/pre-push-checker/last-run.log</code>. A new startup activity parses that log on
                project open and on every hook run, feeds errors into the Compilation Checker tool window,
                and raises a notification with an "Open Compilation Checker" action.</li>
            <li>Managed wrapper is refreshed on every project open so hook upgrades ship automatically.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.1.0</h3>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Tool window:</b> Replaced the "Clear" action with a "Report Issue" action that opens the plugin's GitHub Issues page with a pre-populated, concise title (no large error payload stuffed into the URL).</li>
            <li><b>Readable error list:</b> Entries now render as <code>FileName:line:col — message</code> instead of the raw <code>[full/deep/path (line, col)] message</code>. The full entry is preserved as a tooltip on hover.</li>
            <li><b>Navigation fix:</b> Double-click / Enter now correctly opens the source file for entries that use the <code>[path (line, col)]</code> compiler format. Also supports paths containing spaces.</li>
            <li><b>Pre-push EDT fix:</b> Replaced <code>ModalityState.any()</code> with the progress indicator's modality (falling back to the default) when triggering a compilation from a background thread. Prevents "Write-unsafe context" errors during compile setup.</li>
            <li><b>Robustness:</b> Null-safe compiler-message formatting, exception-isolated listener fan-out in <code>CompilationErrorService</code>, and short-circuit when the new error list equals the previous snapshot.</li>
            <li><b>Performance:</b> Per-extension icon cache in the list renderer, allocation-free source-extension check in <code>PushValidationPaths</code>, reused <code>StringBuilder</code> when formatting compiler messages, and pre-sized result lists.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.0.1</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Fix EDT violation when triggering a compilation check from the tool window Run Check button</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>1.0.0 — Initial Release</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Pre-push handler for the IntelliJ Git Push dialog</li>
            <li>Smart module-level compile scope with automatic full-build fallback</li>
            <li>IDE problem check using WolfTheProblemSolver before triggering a build</li>
            <li>Compilation error dialog with file-type icons, navigation, and Refresh action</li>
            <li>Compilation Checker tool window (right side panel)</li>
            <li>Git hook installer for terminal push support (Gradle &amp; Maven)</li>
            <li>CompilationErrorService for cross-component error state sharing</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.lang</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.java</depends>
    <depends>Git4Idea</depends>

    <!-- Optional soft dependency: JetBrains AI Assistant plugin -->
    <depends optional="true" config-file="commitgen-intellij-ai.xml">com.intellij.ml.llm</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <prePushHandler implementation="com.github.prepushchecker.PrePushCompilationHandler"/>
        <projectActivity implementation="com.github.prepushchecker.PrePushProjectActivities$GitHookInstallerActivity"/>
        <projectActivity implementation="com.github.prepushchecker.PrePushProjectActivities$ExternalPushErrorLoaderActivity"/>
        <projectActivity implementation="com.github.prepushchecker.PrePushProjectActivities$PrePushLocalServerActivity"/>
        <projectActivity implementation="com.github.prepushchecker.PrePushProjectActivities$CompilationWarmupServiceActivity"/>
        <postStartupActivity implementation="com.github.prepushchecker.PrePushLocalServerStartupActivity"/>
        <projectService serviceImplementation="com.github.prepushchecker.CompilationErrorService"/>
        <projectService serviceImplementation="com.github.prepushchecker.CompilationWarmupService"/>
        <projectService serviceImplementation="com.github.prepushchecker.PrePushLocalServer"/>

        <!-- AI Commit Message Generator -->
        <applicationService
            serviceImplementation="com.github.prepushchecker.commitgen.CommitMessageSettings"/>
        <projectService
            serviceImplementation="com.github.prepushchecker.commitgen.CommitMessageGeneratorService"/>
        <applicationConfigurable
            parentId="tools"
            id="com.github.prepushchecker.commitgen.CommitMessageSettingsConfigurable"
            instance="com.github.prepushchecker.commitgen.CommitMessageSettingsConfigurable"
            displayName="Pre-Push Checker — AI Commit Message Generator"/>

        <registryKey key="prepushchecker.warmup.enabled"
                     defaultValue="true"
                     description="Run a debounced background compile of recently saved files so pre-push checks hit the cache and finish instantly."/>
        <registryKey key="prepushchecker.scope.modules.cap"
                     defaultValue="50"
                     description="Maximum number of modules (pushed modules plus their dependents) included in the pre-push compile scope. If exceeded, falls back to file scope to avoid churning the world when a widely-used utility module is pushed."/>
        <notificationGroup id="Pre-Push Compilation Checker"
                           displayType="BALLOON"
                           isLogByDefault="true"/>
        <toolWindow id="Compilation Checker"
                    anchor="right"
                    factoryClass="com.github.prepushchecker.CompilationCheckerToolWindowFactory"
                    icon="/icons/toolWindowCompilation.svg"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action id="CommitMessageGenerator.Generate"
                class="com.github.prepushchecker.commitgen.GenerateCommitMessageAction"
                text="Generate Commit Message (Pre-Push Checker)"
                description="Pre-Push Checker: Generate a commit message from staged changes using the configured AI provider"
                icon="AllIcons.Actions.Lightning">
            <!-- Appears in the Vcs.MessageActionGroup (commit message area context) -->
            <add-to-group group-id="Vcs.MessageActionGroup" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>

    <applicationListeners>
        <listener class="com.github.prepushchecker.PluginLifecycleListener"
                  topic="com.intellij.ide.plugins.DynamicPluginListener"/>
        <listener class="com.github.prepushchecker.CompilationWarmupService$SaveListener"
                  topic="com.intellij.openapi.fileEditor.FileDocumentManagerListener"/>
    </applicationListeners>
</idea-plugin>
